Alex can I become a millionaire from
Trading what is this day trading stuff I
see everywhere can I get started right
now and the answer is yes in this video
I'm going to be showing you how you can
make anywhere from ,000 to $1,500 a week
as a beginner day trader I get these
messages asked every single day on
Instagram and I'm going to answer all of
them in this video this is going to be a
full day trading tutorial I'm going to
show you what is day trading I'm going
to show you the advantag and
disadvantages I'm going to show you how
to enter a trade how to get out how to
withdraw how to do everything literally
all in one spot this is a video that I
wish that I had when I started day
trading this would have sa me hundreds
of hours and thousands of videos that I
look through YouTube to try and figure
out this whole day trading stuff in this
video everything is going to be in here
so first of all what is day trading so
let's point out the advantages and then
let's point out the disadvantages and
this way you can see if it's for you
because if it's not then you just save
yourself some time so what are the
advantages of day trading and I can tell
you right now there's a lot first things
first is fast execution so you enter the
market pretty much immediately that you
want a trade let's say you want to enter
a position Monday morning you can do
that let's say you want to enter a
position Tuesday afternoon you can do
that you can enter position basically
whenever you want because since you're
day trading the market is going to give
you opportunities throughout the whole
entire week the next Advantage is that
it requires some patience not extreme
amount of patience like swing trading
but it does require a good amount of
patience enough for a human to be able
to work on it and get better and it can
almost work to your benefit this way you
grow and you become a better Trader is
also accessible to anybody across the
world you can literally be living in the
United States Latin America Africa
Europe Australia Japan China anywhere
with a computer and Wi-Fi you're able to
be a day trader you can get a solid
opportunity literally every single day
so that's the whole reason of day
trading you can trade every single day
now does it mean that every single day
there's going to be an amazing
opportunity but the opportunity is there
to trade every single day there's a lot
of day traders to learn from but this
can almost be a double-edged sword
because it can almost be information
overload but more on this when we head
to the disadvantages of day trading the
next benefit is that you really don't
have to be in front of the charts all
day because if you're a day trader you
only have to be in front of the markets
a very specific time only a specific
time zone that you want to day trade and
then that's it you can enjoy the rest of
your day you can work on other habits in
your life and get better so doesn't
require a lot of attention and strict
hours for you to be in front of the
computer if you want to be a day trader
another great benefit is once you catch
the trade it's pretty much it you're
done you let the trade hit your stop
loss or you let the trade hit your take
profit which is amazing because this way
you can enjoy the the day you don't have
to be glued in front of the computer
risk reward ratio is another great one
because you are having a minimum of a 1
to2 risk reward ratio now this is very
key and important because you don't have
to have a positive win rate in order to
be profitable if you have a positive
risk to reward ratio this is something a
little bit more into detail but I'm
going to get into that later in this
video but risk to reward ratio is key
because you're going to become more
profitable as a day trader than you can
as a scalper due to positive risk reward
ratio you can have the benefit of only
day trading once or twice a week you
don't have to trade every day the
opportunity is there but if you get a
good trade you only have to trade once
or twice a week and these are just some
of the small advantages that day trading
has so how much money can you actually
earn from day trading and the answer
really depends on your account size and
this number can vary depends as well as
how much you risk so let's put an
example let's say you have a $1,000
account and let's say you risk 2% per
trade and you end up the month with a
10% profit while there you're going to
only make1 because $100 is 10% of $1,000
now but you take that same percentage to
now let's say $110,000 so let's say you
do the same thing $10,000 you risk 2%
and throughout the whole month you make
another 10% but on that 10,000 now
you've made $1,000 not super attractive
but the percentage is what matters
because now if we take that same 10%
principle to let's say $100,000 and then
you risk the same 2% of the account you
scale up 10% throughout the whole period
of the month now you have made $10,000
in one month risking 2% now this is
extremely key because this shows you how
we using the same exact percentage but
on a different account size and you can
obviously seek funding there is hundreds
of funding companies out there there's
many different evaluation processes to
do and there's people ready and eager to
throw money at you and invest in you as
a day trader once you are profitable
because you're going to basically make
these people money you just have to do a
profit split on the money that you make
them that's how I got to the position
that I am today I got funded and I made
28,00 000 in a month and I had a 7030
profit split with that investor and
basically I got 70% of the profits that
person got 30% of the profits and we
were very happy so how much money can
you earn with day trading there is no
cap there is no limit to what you can
make with day trading it just depends
how well are you with that skill set the
better you are with the skill set the
more money you can seek the better
profit SP you can have in your advantage
the more money you're going to make but
it all starts with the principle of the
skill set once you learn the skill set
the the money will come by itself I can
guarantee you that and I'm living proof
of that how much money do you need to
get started into day trading and the
answer is whatever you're willing to put
in just already picture that money that
you're putting in as a loss because this
money that you first deposit in it's
going to require some hard lessons it's
going to require risk management
mandatory stop-loss mandatory trade
management mandatory risk to reward it's
going to require a lot for you to
actually understand what trading is and
all of these things is going to be
learned in your first deposit into the
accounts so what is the right amount for
you to get started well what is the
right amount that you're willing to lose
from the beginning what is an amount
that you have no emotional attachment to
everybody has a different financial
position so if you are in a better
position than others put what you are
willing to risk if you're not in a
better position than others then put
what you're willing to risk don't
compare your beginning to my beginning
or my beginning to somebody else at
beginning because we all start from a
different point but we all start with
the same base and that is knowing
nothing and the only way we know the
stuff is by the lessons that the market
is are about to give us and those
lessons end up costing us money so I
would start with something very small
could be as small as $100 $200 something
that's not significant to you so you are
ready to lose it you learn those lessons
and then you come back and deposit again
and then you learn from your mistakes or
instead of depositing into account you
can get a funded account and try it that
way but I personally don't recommend
that because at the beginning the
evaluation process is they have very
tedious rules like the draw down and all
that stuff so I think it's best if you
just go deposit into your own account
and then you start from there where
there is pretty much no rules you make
your own rules so what do you need
exactly to get started day trading right
what are the actual keys do you need a
book do you need a specific keypad do
you need a crazy monitor is there
something special that you need to get
started into day trading so you actually
start making money and the answer is no
you need nothing special everything that
you're watching this video through right
now is enough to become a profitable
Trader with so the first things first
you need a PC you need a laptop you need
a computer you need something so you can
actually see the charts in because
you're obviously trading the charts next
you need a trading view account you need
a metat trator account you need a
trading strategy a trading plan and
extreme discipline and all of these
things I'm going to explain into this
video especially how you create those
first accounts how you create the
trading view how you create the man
trador all of that I'm going to teach
you in this very video which took me a
lot of time to actually understand what
I needed versus what I didn't need so
now I'm going to actually show you how
the day trading charts look like now
don't get intimidated don't worry I'm
just going to summarize the very very
fast so you get a feel of it and you
understand what the day trading charts
look like and then after I explain it in
a very brief summary it can take 30
seconds to a minute and I'm going to go
into detail on every single aspect of
the trading view account the
candlesticks the lines everything that
looks like a lot of information at first
I'm going to break it down but first I
just want you to get an awareness of
what the charts look like so don't get
intimidated I'm going to give you guys a
visualization of what to expect when I
break it down as soon as I explain so
we're here in trading VI this is where
we're going to analyze our trades every
single morning every single night right
before we take a trade we always have to
see it here first so what I'm going to
show you guys is what trading view is
how to actually see a day trade and how
to spot it whether it's going up or
whether it's going down and then after
I'm going to literally explain what all
of these things are here to the right
what are these things that are moving up
and down what are all these tools to the
left what are these buttons up here
literally everything that you're seeing
in front of you right now I'm going to
explain to you very very very soon
because I know it can look very
intimidating at the beginning so first
things first when you enter any Market
of day trading you need to see if it's
going up or it is going down this is
also known as if the price were to be
bullish or if price were to be bearish
this is very key because if price is
bullish you're buying if price is
bearish you are selling and this example
right here doesn't take much you know
knowledge to realize that price is
headed to the upside you guys can see
here how the market structure is
actually moving to the up and when I
mean Market structure that means that
this Market is consisting of higher
highs and higher lows these higher highs
and higher lows is what identifies us in
in the market to be able to tell whether
we are bullish or bearish this example
right here this is what is called a
level of a higher high right here and
then this is a level of a higher low
these lines right here these sharp
rejections in price those are also known
as elbows and this is what identifies us
that price doesn't like that area and
it's rejecting it so as you can see
Price Right Here rejected this area if
you look a little bit to the left what
do you see that price rejected that area
as well but to head to the downside now
when we are above it it shows that we're
going to reject it to the upside so this
right here is a solid area of Market
structure so every single point that is
a high point it's a higher high and then
a higher low so this right here would be
a higher low then this point right here
would be a higher high this point over
here this would be a higher high and
then this would be a higher low now keep
in mind it is literally impossible for
you to have a bullish Market structure
without a higher high or higher low if
you don't have a higher high or higher
low it is impossible to have a bullish
Market structure and also it is
literally impossible for you to have a
bearish market structure without a lower
low or a lower high to also see it very
clearly you can see right here this we
would also lose it as a line we would
mark off here higher high which is HH
and then the higher low would be the
last structure point right here so we
would just get this line right here and
then this would be the high or low so as
long as price remains in between these
two zones price is still bullish let's
say if we were to do something like this
that we then continue to head to the
upside now we have a new higher higher
why because we have broken above the
previous high so this is the new higher
high so we move this point right here
and then the last higher low it moves
because this is no longer the last
higher low this is the last higher low
right here and as long as price keeps
doing this we keep moving the higher low
and higher high points so it keeps
heading to wherever it decides to head
to so for example here it broke again
this is the new higher high this point
right here turns into the high or low so
this is how you identify whether the
market is bullish or bearish which is
the first thing that you want to do and
it's actually one of the most important
things in any strategy next thing is
where are you going to be buying where
you going to be selling you're going to
be buying or selling at an area of
Interest so what is an area of Interest
how do I spot one how do I know if it's
a real one how do I know if it's a fake
one very simple an a of interest is a
spot where it has more than three
touches so more than three touches means
that price has gone to that area and
it's rejected it more than three times
so this point right here you see how it
was under and it rejected it so this is0
one you can see how this point right
here price came to it and then it
rejected it this is point two and then
you can see right here how whenever
price got to this point and then it
rejected it that is point three now
doesn't matter if it rejected it from
the downside three times rejected to the
upside three times as long as price
rejects this point right here that is
what we want to see so a perfect area of
interest that we can see right now in
price would let let's say be this point
right around here just for example
surpasses this would be an area of
interest because we have one two and
then three touches so this would be an
area of Interest price has retested that
area and then this is where we would be
looking to enter the trade this is where
we would use our risk to reward tool
this literally tells us how much we're
going to lose and how much we're going
to gain that's what I said earlier
remember key with day trading is risk to
reward and that's exactly what this tool
is right here this tool shows you what
you are risking which is in the red
versus the reward which is what you're
gaining which is in the green and this
right here measures the amount of points
also known as Pips and your stop- loss
and then also the amount of points or
Pips in the takeprofit also the risk to
reward ratio which is what I mentioned
to you guys which is one of the most key
important things tells you that right
now you are risking $1 to make
$145 obviously this is if you're risking
$1 you're risking $100 to make
$145 this is not a good risk to reward
you need to have a minimum of a two
points risk to reward ratio now again
this might be information overload and
it's not trust me I'm going to explain
everything now in great detail but I
just want you guys to get a feel of what
it looks like with the day trading
charts and everything so we're going to
take a couple steps back now and I'm
going to explain everything in great
detail so let's take the first steps let
me get your charts to look just like
mine because as soon as you create your
trading view account it's not going to
look like my chart so let's do that
right now so you're going to go over to
tradingview.com which is where pretty
much I think 99% of the traders in the
industry watch their charts we're going
to create an account right now and then
we're going to put your trading view
exactly as I have mine so you can see
the charts with the same clarity as I do
so you're just going to head here to the
top right section right where it says
get started soon as you click get
started sign up for the Z you do not
have to sign up and pay the subscription
you just simply sign up it's going to
give you an option to sign up with your
Google account Facebook X Apple all that
stuff so sign in however you want and
then as soon as you sign in this is
what's going to pop up so as soon as you
sign sign in with your Google account
it's going to ask you to create your
name so this is where I'm just going to
put for example of this name we're going
to put Alex G YouTube video so I don't
want to receive any offers but I have
read the terms and conditions so as soon
as you sign in it's going to give you
the option here to then put your name
for this example I'm just going to put
alexg 1-6 I have already read the terms
and conditions you have to do that very
simple then you just simply click next
and then here it's going to ask you to
now have a subscription you guys don't
need this right now this is not do that
at all it's just extra features I think
I spent almost 2 years years without
paying the subscription at all the only
reason you pay for the subscription is
simply just to not have the ads so once
you're here and you already have your
account you're going to Simply go to
then markets you're going to hit the
overview button and then you're going to
see how all of these indices stocks
Futures and then Forex and cryptos pop
up so you can click Forex you can click
Euro USD as soon as you click it then
you can click on C super charts and this
as soon as you click this it's going to
take you to the actual charts that you
were just looking at and right off the
bat back you can see how this doesn't
look like mine right why does this look
uglier why doesn't this look as clean
that's simply because over the years I
have analyzed my charts so much and I've
figured out the correct pattern on how
to have them clean so first things first
that you want to do is you want to
remove all the noise you want to take
off all the stuff that don't matter so
for example this volume down here you're
simply going to double click it you're
going to go to visibility and then
you're just not going to have it visible
at all not on the weekly not on the
daily not on the hours you just don't
want to have this visible at all and you
simply just put okay so that's gone so
now you're only focusing on the charts
we're going to head over here to the
watch list and as of right now we don't
trade indices we don't trade stocks we
don't trade Futures so what do we need
to have all that noise less is more when
it comes to trading so you just want to
click this little x button right here
and then you're going to remove all of
these pairs from your watch list if you
bu accidentally exited out on the Forex
pairs don't worry I'm going to teach you
how to add it back it's very simple so
you're just going to exit out on all of
these stuff here that are not necess
necessary Futures gold silver all that
stuff and then we're going to also
remove the cryptos right so now we're
only left with the Forex pairs because
again remember less is more in this
industry now that you have this cleaned
out and you're only focused on the
currency pairs you have to make sure
you're on the right server what is that
mean what is this right here you guys
can see how this is the Euro and the
dollar and how we are on the daily time
frame but we are on the server fxcm so
the fxcm server you can see how it has
gaps you see right here how this has a
gap Gap you can see how this has a gap
how this has a gap and this Gap can be
very confusing at the beginning because
a lot of Traders they don't know what to
do or with that information so this is
where we're simply going to just type on
the on the keyboard just going to put
Euro USD and this is going to pop up
this is the server that we are currently
on right now fxcm fxcm and it has gaps
you don't want the gaps you want to be
on EUR USD but you want to be on the o
and the server so I'm just going to tap
on this really fast and you can see how
all of those gaps were filled you can
see how clean it looks you can see how
there's no gaps in this market so if I
go back and I click this server right
here you can see how then it goes back
to the fxcm server and there's gaps
versus if I type up Euro USD once again
and then I put the oanda one then
there's no gaps so you want to have all
of the markets that you're looking to
trade on the oanda server now how do you
get that to this section here very easy
you simply come here and then you flag
it as red so when you you go up here to
your watch list you go to your watch
list that is red and then boom now the
Euro USD with the oand the server pops
up let say we want to add another pair
gbpusd we go here to the oanda server
you tap on it click up here the red flag
boom pops up here that's it that is
yours forever whatever you do here is
going to literally stay here for life so
now that we've added this currency pair
to our watch list you can go on and you
can add as many currencies pairs as you
want you can add the main ones USD JPY
GBP JPY literally any currency pair that
you want pretty much just come in here
type it up and then you just add it very
easy some people they only have one some
people have two three I personally have
I think it's 13 14 15 different currency
pairs that I added over the time but
that's not the point right now what is
the point right now is you want to make
your charts look like mine so before we
actually get into the charts I want to
make sure that you have all of the time
frames that you need so you're going to
click up here this D because this is the
one day so meaning every single one of
these candlestick are 24 hours as you
can see this Candlestick right here has
about 21 hours left before it closes so
this was yesterday's Candlestick which
was November 1st this was October 31st
this was October 30th and how am I
seeing that date you guys can see it
down here literally all the way at the
bottom you guys can see how it says the
date right down there changes as I go
through the candlesticks so now you want
to hit this little d right here and
these are all the time frames that pop
up you do not need all of these time
frames less is more keep that in mind
mind so the time frames that I use and
have made me successful and have gotten
me these type of profits or even these
type of profits is by simply using these
time frames right here you do not need
to add any other time frame it's going
to be the 15 minute the 30 minute the 1
hour the 2 hour the 4our the daily the
weekly and the monthly so what you want
to do is you want to put a star over
those time frames because what that does
is that as soon as you exit out of here
notice how all of these time frames have
popped up so now no matter where you are
you can just simply tap here and now you
know you're on the 4our you know you're
on the 2hour you know you're on the
daily everything is very clear cuz all
the time frames are up here together
next thing is you want to make sure your
candlesticks look like mine right so
let's actually get into the charts so
you just double click this you want to
make sure the bodies of the candlesticks
are black and the way you get there is
by clicking the candlesticks two times
and sorry the bodies of the candlesticks
you want to make sure that they are blue
so if they're headed up you want them to
be blue if they're headed down you want
them to be red the borders they have to
be black on both of these right here and
then the Wicks you want to make sure
that they are black as well so you can
just focus on what matters which is the
actual candlesticks of the price next
you want to go to I think it is canvas
there you go and you do not want to have
any horizontal lines so any horizontal
or vertical lines simply just make them
white get this one and make it white so
now you notice you have a beautiful
clean chart that all you see is price
action you don't need to have all those
lines in the back you don't need to have
a watermark uh because if I don't know I
don't know why people like having the
water marks in the back I feel like it
just covers price up cuz I say you're
looking at Price like this you literally
can't see price because of the watermark
if you want to know what pair it is
simply just look to the top left corner
or look up here or look over here it's
so many places that you can see the
currency pair that you don't need the
watermark that's the last thing that you
need so if you want to remove a
watermark come here to Canvas and you
just exit out the watermark as of right
now your chart is looking exactly like
mine you have the same color Candlestick
the same Wix you have the time frames
you have the server all you're missing
is now the actual strategy and many more
things right but let me actually hook
you guys up with the actual tools as
well so the tools that I use are very
simple you can come to here and you're
going to see a bunch of extra stuff that
you don't need it's very unnecessary you
only need a certain amount of stuff and
this is what you need you're going to
need a horizontal line going to need a
head and shoulders patterns you're going
to need a long position a short position
you're going to need brush you're going
to need a rectangle you're going to need
a circle and anything that you need you
simply just put a star on it and it's
going to pop up up over here you're
going to need a t this T is so you write
a text message into your box and then
one last thing that I forgot here it's
going to be your path this path is very
key and very important this is all that
you need from everything that is in here
you do not need the cipher pattern you
don't need the ABC pattern you don't
need the triangle the Elliot the
Fibonacci you don't need none of that
stuff all you need is Market structure
risk Ro ratio and a nice area of
interest and these are all the tools
you're are going to need to succeed with
trading I'm going to teach you how to
use every single one of them in this
video because if you use them right you
can capitalize off of it if you use them
wrong well then you obviously won't make
any money trading so let me explain to
you guys what every single one of these
tools are in this toolbox bar now this
toolbox bar you can move it around you
can put it anywhere you want don't be
scared of it it's not scared of you you
can literally hide it put it wherever
you want if you don't want to see it
simply just click this little star and
it disappears if you want it back it's
going to pop up wherever the last time
that you left it so if you want to move
them around inside here you simply just
grab them and then you can also move
them inside here but for right now let's
start off with the actual horizontal Ray
so you can just tap it and put it
anywhere you want in the chart you can
move it up you can move it down once
again you don't have to be scared of it
it's not going to do anything to you you
can double click it change the color it
could be blue it could be black could be
yellow could be orange whatever color
you want I always recommend to go black
so it's the same color as the bodies and
I would also recommend to not have it
too thick I would recommend to put it as
thin as it can so once you click it
click on the color you put it black you
make sure you put the thickness the
thinnest line this way when you line up
price it gets to a very precise Point
versus if you were to have a big block
like this it just looks very very choppy
it doesn't look that clean so the
Slimmer the better because that's what
we're going to use with the actual box
and we're going to get into that in just
a second so the second tool that we have
is the head and shoulders pattern now
how do you use this where is there Head
and Shoulders patterns in the chart I
can't find it how do I know it's a real
head and shoulders and as of right now
right in front of you guys there is two
head and shoulders patterns literally
right in front of you guys right now
might not look like this it might look
like an inverted Head and Shoulders
which actually looks a little bit
different looks like this and I'm going
to give you guys a minute to try and
find it so pause the video and try and
find the head and shoulders pattern in
this market you didn't find it all right
let me show you where it is so this is
why they call it a head and shoulders
pattern right because it has a left the
head and then the right shoulder left
head and the right shoulder so this is a
reversal pattern this happens at the top
of a trend and then this happens at a
bottom of the trend so if price is
moving to the upside and it's going to
to now reverse to the downside usually
what happens is that at the top of a
trend it forms a head and shoulders
pattern where then it does this
formation and then after this formation
what it does is that price now starts
going to then the downside is a reversal
pattern same thing as let's say we reach
a bottom of price then price decides to
do a reversal pattern which is known as
the head and shoulders and this is where
it decides to then head to the upside if
you guys can see this is the head and
shoulders pattern right here simply
follow following what price is done left
head right shoulder if you guys want to
know more about reversal patterns and
other ones just like this left Head and
Shoulders click this link right here and
there's a video where I explained
everything about reversal patterns Head
and Shoulders double bottom spinning
tops engulfing everything when it comes
to the best reversal patterns that I use
in the markets that help me generate
amazing numbers when I trade so this
head and shoulders patterns right here
we can actually see it right at the
bottom of this market price right here
now don't get mad if it's your first
time seeing it on you're not actually
able to notice it cuz it's very
difficult at the beginning but once you
see it you almost can't unsee it it's
like where's Waldo once you see wdo you
can't unsee Waldo you see here you have
left you have the head and then you have
the right shoulder that has formed right
here so if I were to get this and I were
to just move it to the upside you can
see the clean Head and Shoulders pattern
and patterns like this are literally
everywhere they come in all types of
sizes and shapes you can see a very
large one right here left head and then
you can see the right shoulder and
there's many different ways how you can
spot it and use this to your advantage
so this is just a tool and we're going
to later down the video use it to
actually enter a trade and make money
trading with this pattern but that for
right now is the head and shoulders
pattern how you can spot it and how you
can use it as well next is going to be
the rist to reward ratio tool so we
going to have the one for buys and
you're going to have the one for sells
so the rist reward ratio tool tells you
what you are going to risk and what you
are going to gain for what you risk now
this can be moved this can be adjusted
so you want to risk less amount of Pips
or points you can move it up and down
you want to make more Pips or points you
can move it up or down really depends on
your liking but if you're going to buy a
trade you have to have this tool right
here so you can spot the trade when it's
going to head up if you're going to sell
a trade you need to use this tool so you
can put out the risk reward when it's
going to head to the downside now now
this risk reward tool this information
here it's very simple literally tells
you exactly what you're going to risk in
terms of points so this right here for
example is 164 points and you're going
to have a 250 Point takeprofit also
known as Pips they say you want to risk
less amount of Pips usually people risk
anywhere from 20 to 50 Pips this right
here is where you can average out your
pip sizing for example this would be a
40 pip stop loss for let's say a
realistic
20 145 pip gain so this is a solid one
to3 risk reward ratio now this example
right here is only to be used if you are
buying a trade so this right here would
be a perfect example of you buying a
trade it hitting your takeprofit and
then you are out before it hits your
stop loss same thing for the sales if
you want to have a small stop loss you
just want to have a 40 to 50 point stop
loss tells you right here 43 Pips you
can make it even smaller 27 Pips and you
can to have your take profit bigger or
smaller and same thing you can put it
right here in the chart and it's going
to tell you where you got into the trade
and exactly how you got out this is very
key because is literally going to tell
you when you're making money in the
market and when you're losing money in
the market so this risk reward ratio
tools are very key very important next
you have your brush brush is just if you
want to spot something out something
extra you really don't need it I just
like using it because when I do zooms
with the students I'm always writing in
the charts everywhere and I'm always
pointing things out so you probably
might not need it I just consciously put
it on here the next very important tool
is going to be the rectangle so this
rectangle again you can put it up down
you can put it however you want but
before that let me show you guys the
coloring you can make the coloring
however you'd like I recommend you make
it the colors that I have it so we look
at the same things when we're looking at
the markets this way you can actually
have a similarity to the way how I break
down the charts and this is by having
the same ristor reward tools the same
candlesticks the same everything so I
have a red outline then I have that
color blue which actually looks very
nice because it pops the red and the
blue pop red candlesticks down blue
Candlestick up matches perfectly so this
tool is to be used to find areas of
Interest supports and resistance levels
if you notice this line right here has
this level of support support and
resistance but it's not perfect if you
notice the line missed this point right
here it went a little bit over here it
didn't catch these bodies here that's
exactly what this rectangle is the
rectangle is it's to bring everybody in
together you want to make sure you have
something around this sizing with the
line in the middle so it's actually
compacting everything and it makes it
very clean because price is never going
to always break an area then come back
and touch the exact number that you
placed and then head to the upside very
rare that that happens usually it hits a
Zone which has anywhere from 10 to 20 to
30 Pips and then it decides to move in
that direction for example this zone
right here is actually 30 Pips which is
a solid zone for price to reach and then
head to the direction that you're
expecting to it again keep in mind we
are on the daily time frame so this is
what this tool is used for usually you
can see it on my charts pretty much
everywhere they going to be lines like
this where you're going to see it tap
you know resistance support resistance
resistance support ah so on and so forth
and it's very important because this is
what's going to tell me when price is
going to break and retest the level of
support so I can actually enter a trade
so this is probably one of my other most
important tools and it's very very
effective next we have the circle circle
is the same thing whether you want to
mark off an area where you want price to
come into I personally like using it
when I'm also teaching because this way
I can Vis like I can literally show you
what I'm looking at in the charts so
let's say I'm looking at this structure
point right here you know I'm talking
about this structure point right here
versus if I say all right you see that
structure point right at the left
shoulder you have no idea what I'm
talking about ver I say this is the left
shoulder you know what I'm talking about
also it's just to remember certain
things that happen so let's say
something happened here in my strategy
that didn't work just put the circle
there and I can come back and look at it
whenever I want next is going to be the
T this T is actually the text you can
write here whatever notes you want
literally whatever notes you want that
you can leave to yourself it's going to
be very important that you do this
because this is what I actually use to
write down my confluences every single
time I enter a trade and this is
something that has been holding me
accountable whenever I enter a trade
because I am literally writing down why
should I enter why should I not enter
what did I do wrong what did I do right
and again all of this stays here on
trading view I can literally go to
another pair I can go to gbpusd for a
say and come back and all this is going
to stay here forever it'll stay in the
trading view server it's never going to
go anywhere so this text is where we
write down our confluences writes down
what we're waiting for in a current
spare literally everything is what's
going to be used for this text and you
can use it as as many times as you want
for as many notes and as many messages
as you want next is going to be the path
which I see you guys already see that I
use it a lot it's going to be just a
line up Market structure gets you a
really good feel of what the actual
lines of the chart are doing again once
once again it's also really good just
for noting so these are all the tools
that you're going to need from the
actual tools to the left hand side
everything else here pretty much
pointless this measuring tool is just to
measure the amount of Pips so if you
want to measure up and down this would
pretty much tell you how many Pips it is
and how many bars which in this case it
would be six days and it just it's a
measuring tool I've never used this
magnet I've never used this I've never
used this I've never used this it's just
say you want to remove all the drawings
temporarily just go like that but you
want to bring it back go like that I've
never found a need to do that so
everything here we already understand
what it is everything else up here this
would be these type of candlesticks that
we are on right now so we are on the the
Japanese candlesticks you can favor that
if you want you can come here go to the
line chart you can go to pretty much any
type of chart you want but we're only
trading the Candlestick pattern so
there's really no need to explain what
all of these are I have no idea what any
of these are actually and I never use
them indicators I don't really use mine
pointless but there is a video on that
as well if you want to know about it
just click this video right here I have
a video explaining my EMA and how it
works next is going to be this tool
right here I've never used this in my
life next we have the alerts which which
I can actually explain how that works so
let's say you want price to notify you
once it reaches this area of Interest
this is where you would put this little
line right here if you notice if you get
close to it you see how there's a plus
sign so I would just come here I would
click the plus sign and i' would put add
an alert so if I click that you see
immediately there is this alarm so this
is a live alarm so as soon as price on
EUR USD reaches 1.06 3181 it will notify
my phone instantly it will let me know
that price is there so alarms are useful
because let's say you're waiting for
price to get to this area in order for
you to sell so let's say you're waiting
for something like this in order to
enter the trade it will notify you as
soon as it reaches that point in order
so you can pay attention to the chart
and you can actually take the trade so
this example right here is very well
useful because I use alarms all of the
time and that's the only reason I got
the subscription on trading view is
because of the actual alarms because I
think the free version they cap you at
three or four and then if you pay you
you get way more so if you want to
remove the alarm click that X right
there and it's going to ask you if you
want to remove the alert and yes if you
want to add it again tap it add it boom
it's there you want to remove it hover
over it remove it that's it it's very
easy next is going to be the replay so
the replay is used for back testing um I
personally don't back test myself I
haven't done it I don't encourage any of
my students to back test we only live
test forward because when you back test
you're almost kind of cheating because
you already saw what price is going to
do so it's like you can't even pretend
that you don't know what price is going
to do right now but it's a tool that you
can you know mess around a little bit
with and it pretty much plays price back
in the future I mean it I'm sorry it
plays back price in the past so you can
predict what happens in the future but
we technically already saw what happen
in the future so to me it's pointless
and then this point right here is like
let's say that we do something and we
mess up on the chart we simply just
click this button right here and it
takes us back kind of how it is with
Microsoft Word and whenever you're
writing an essay you just click back all
of these buttons up here I never used
them never use publish I never use any
of these buttons over here as well to me
all these things are pointless I never
use this at all I sometimes just use it
to move up and down just to kind of hide
the pairs that I'm trading or not but
for me this is useless as well and same
thing with down here I don't use
anything of over here I simply just
focus on the charts and that is it
everything else here is extremely
unnecessary only focusing on what
matters which is the actual charts
itself okay so now we understand what
trading view is so again trading view is
where you're going to Simply analyze the
markets this is where you're going to
mark up your trades you're going to put
your areas of Interest your alarms your
risk of reward ratios where you want to
actually enter the trades where you're
going to identify whether you want to
buy or whether you want to sell but now
you're ready to take that buy or you're
ready to take that sell so what do you
do well this is where you have to go to
metat Trader 4 and metat Trader 5 on
your phone and then you have to download
these apps in order for you to actually
execute on these trades and this is very
key because these are the platforms that
99% of the market uses and it's very
simple and very effective to use it I've
been using them since I got started and
thanks to this platform I'm able to
execute to the market immediately so
medat Trad 4 is let's say the iPhone 10
medat Trader 5 is the iPhone 14 so for
this video example I'm going to be
showing you this example on how to
actually use it on metat Trader 5 which
is the latest iPhone so there is
obviously different ways that you can
access metat Trader 5 you can do it on
your desktop on your phone I've always
done it on my phone it's the easiest and
most accessible thing and realistically
every every single broker out there uses
metatrader 4 medit Trader 5 you can't
just go to medat Trader 4 and medit
Trader 5 and send the money there no you
have to use a broker a platform let's
say oanda.com or IC markets or forex.com
and those Brokers they connect your
money to this platform so you deposit
your money into the broker and once the
money is in the broker the broker
transfers it into this platform and this
is where you actually execute the trade
so right now what we're going to do is
we're going to create a demo account
also known as as paper trading and we're
going to take trades in the live market
you can take trades in the live market
with fake money because this way you can
test out your strategy you can test out
the broker you can see the different
market conditions that they actually
have to offer and that's what we're
going to do right now on metat Trader 5
so I'm just going to click on metat
Trader 5 and the first thing that it's
going to ask is open a demo account so
what we're going to do that we're going
to do that together so we're going to
click open a demo account as soon as you
click that it just creates your account
so you guys can see here this is the
quotes the chart trade history and then
the setting so right off the bat they
gave us $100,000 to trade obviously it
is demo money you can see at the top
right badge up there you can see how it
says demo so this is where you want to
pretty much go to the quote section and
then here you are able to freely take
the same trade that you were analyzing
on the actual trading view if you notice
the first currency pair is Euro USD
which is the one the first one that we
were analyzing on trading View the
second one is GBP USD and the one that
we're identifying the trend is USD JP
wat let's say you want to add another
currency pair that you happen to find
simply just click on the search bar and
then you type it in so let's say GBP JPY
click that little green button and now
it is automatically added to the bottom
of your watch list let's say you want to
remove some pairs let's say you want to
remove these pairs right here because
for some reason simply don't like them
you click the pencil at the top right
corner you tap them and then you click
on the garbage can but don't worry that
doesn't mean that they're gone forever
if you want to get them them back search
on the on the search bar and then you
can literally just add them again and
they're back on your watch list so this
is the main section where you can see
the different types of currency Pairs
and you can actually execute it so you
were to tap it you can click trade chart
details statistics depth of Market all
of this stuff but realistically the only
button you're going to use here is going
to be the actual trade button it's the
only button you need I've never used any
other button from here I've never used
the chart I've never used the details
the statistics step I've never used none
of that stuff and it it's completely
unnecessary in my opinion like I'm
always saying less is more so say you
actually want to execute a trade you
would click trade but before we get to
that I just want to show you what every
single other button means so you're up
to speed next is the chart so if you
notice this chart is the same one that
we were looking at on trading view but
if you notice it looks uglier here now
you might be asking yourself why am I
analyzing the charts on trading View and
then taking it on metatrader why don't I
just analyze the charts on on metatrader
and taking it on metatrader and that
simple answer is it's because metatrader
charting platform is very outdated it's
very whack it's very tacky so this is
why you want to use trading view because
it is the new and the latest version of
charting you have alarms everything
looks so much more clean versus on metat
Trader 4 metat Trader 5 it's very
outdated so this is why we use trading
view to analyze and then metat Trader 4
met tra or five to actually execute the
trade so here you you can just see the
charts but it's pointless I never look
at the charts through here because I
always look at the charts through the
actual trading view platform next is the
trade so whenever you actually execute a
trade you can see the floating price of
the account you can see your balance
your equity and the margin that you
currently have on your account and then
you can have your history so here you
can you know sort out your history from
let's say the last 6 months the last
three months the last month custom
however you want this is what you
present to investors so you can show
them hey look I'm Legit I know how to
make money trading give me money so I
make money for you and then all the way
at the right is sensitive information
this is where you can see your account
number you can see what broker you're
using Create a new account so on and so
forth I never use any of the buttons I
don't use the mailbox the news the trade
days the chat the messages Traders
Community the interface the charts the
journal setting I didn't use any of that
stuff ever only thing I ever do is I
either click on the top button right
here which is on the actual metatrader
and let's say I'm going to create a new
account or I'm logging into a new
account I would click the plus button I
would search up the broker so let's say
I'm using oanda I would search up the
and the server once I click on the o and
the server then I'd put the login number
password and then I'm logged in if I
wanted to be a live account so on and so
forth I do that then but I don't use any
of these other buttons like it's all
extremely unnecessary so let's go back
to the quote section because we're going
to actually take a trade together right
now so let's say the USD JPY trade the
one that we were just breaking down
right here the one that I was an
analyzing to buy to the upside let's
take that trade together right now so if
you were to take USD JP y together I
would simply click on USD JPY and then I
would click trade it's going to take me
to this option right here where I can
immediately enter the trade again keep
in mind you are not going to be using
the chart the details the statistics or
the depth of the market none of that
stuff is necessary only the trade button
once you click trade it's going to give
you the option if you want an instant
execution buy limit sell limit buy stop
sell stop buy stop limit sell stop limit
none of that stuff you are immediately
going to enter the market Market as soon
as you click that buy or that sell
button now this is very key because you
need to be very careful with clicking
that button because as soon as you click
it you're in the market it can be a big
mistake if you put the wrong lot size so
right under instant execution you're
going to have your lot size as of right
now we are risking
0.50 per trade and that decimal point
always moves one to the right meaning
that that is what you're risking so if
you were to move that decimal point one
to the right you're risking $5
per pip so if on the USD JPY trade we
had a 20 pip stop loss you pull out your
calculator it's very simple you have 20
Pips times $5 you're risking a total of
$100 on this trade if let's say you want
to risk more let's say you want to risk
$7 per this trade you would put
0.70 because again that decimal point
moves one point to the right always so
now you would pull out the calcul you
would put 20 Pips * $7 equal $140 you're
going to be risking now let's say you
want to up your lot size let's say you
want to risk
1.50 so now this is not 150 this is
actually
$115 per pip so again the decimal point
is going to move one point to the right
and this is where you're going to be
risking $15 per pip so again let's do
the same exact example let's say we are
risking 20 Pips and now you're risking
$15 per per pip you're not risking $300
per trade I'm sure you guys get the memo
so whatever you're willing to risk you
can just pull out that simple calculator
it's very simple right so for this
example let's go a little bit bigger
right it's fake money it's demo you can
go as big as you want so let's simply
put
20 so this means that we are risking
$200 per trade again the decimal point
moves one point to the right so we're
going to be risking $200 per trade we're
going to come here we put $200 per pip
times 20 Pips that equals $4,000 that
we're risking on this trade our stop
loss points this is where we would go to
our stop loss on the actual trading view
chart and then we would identify where
is it that we want to put our stop- loss
so for this example's purposes we're
just going to Simply put a round
psychological level looking at it here
on the chart and we have
149. and then our takeprofit let's just
put it at
1.52
0 so now that we're ready to take the
trade you just click request it's going
to actually give you the live updated
price so now for this example let's
click buy so we're going to click the
buy and then we are immediately entered
into the market so you guys can see
right there how we are already
immediately in a $100 loss and just like
that we are in the live market now that
$100 loss isn't because the price moved
down it's simply because that's the cost
of doing business with this broker so as
of right now this trade is in the live
market we are now down $212 which is
very normal because it's just the feeds
of the broker and this is where we would
see our trade floating in profit so if
you were to tap the trade if you were to
want to close the position you'd click
close if you'd want to modify the
position you'd click modify and those
are the only two buttons you'd actually
click but I only recommend closing the
position when you are actually in profit
so right here You' have to obviously
request the live price because price is
always moving and then you would have
the close price right there at $1 $50
loss so this is actually what what
happens when you enter a trade you're
going immediately see red but it is more
than normal now obviously what we have
just done is just taken a trade at
random we didn't really go into depth in
the actual analysis right now it is
currently 8:45 p.m. EST and we are not
trading in a trading session so that is
not according to my plan so now we're
going to dive into the topic of actually
having a solid trading plan because if
you just take trades like that crazy the
market spreads are going to eat you
you're not going to be trading when
there's a lot of volume in the markets
and you're not trading with the pl so
you're simply not going to be successful
so this is all just an examples purposes
just so I can show you guys exactly how
you analyze the charts how you enter the
trade but now let's actually talk about
a day trading plan so now your plan has
to consist of many things many things
and you cannot not have one of these
things in your trading plan this is
almost like an engine of a car you need
everything to work perfect in order for
the car to run you need the alternator
to cool the engine you need the spark
plugs to ignite the Pistons you need the
oil so it smoothens the way the Pistons
work you need the gas so you fuel the
engine you need the transmission so you
move the car you need the wheels so the
actual car moves like everything is
needed for the car to move you cannot
have one of these pieces out because
then the car won't run it's the same
thing with this trading plan everything
has to be there perfectly in order for
this trading plan to execute and for you
to become profitable do not try to find
any shortcuts because it simply won't
work and it's going to cost you a lot of
time and you're going to waste a lot of
money so the first things first with any
trading plan is you need to have a set
risk percentage what are you willing to
risk of your account whether it's is
going to be a percentage whether it is
going to be a dollar amount stick to
that percentage or stick to that dollar
amount every single time I always
recommend percentage because percentage
moves with the dollar amount of the
account for that trade that we just took
right now we risk $4,000 on that trade
$4,000 on the $100,000 account is simply
4% of the account so that should show
you that you should focus on percentage
and not dollar amount so risk the same
percentage every single time that is
supposed to be your number one rule with
your trading plan next is going to be
the operation hour so there's different
sessions in the market you have Asia
session you have Tokyo you have New York
London and then you have an overlap of
New York and London session you should
only be trading New York or London
session or a little bit before London or
a little bit before New York but never
after New York because there's simply no
volume in the market this is very key
because you're entering the market when
there's movement when the market is
going to hit your take profit a lot
faster when the market is going to move
in that direction a lot faster right now
it's 8:48 at night we are far from
London session London session starts at
3:00 a.m. my time so I just took a trade
6 hours in advance of a session so that
means that this trade is going to be
floating in live market price for the
next 6 hours before any actual volume
kicks into the market and that's going
to be beating up my account into London
session hits and we're currently down
$500 on that trade simply because I
didn't take the trade at the right time
time with the right volume next you need
to have a maximum of Trades you have to
take every single day or every single
week this is a rule that I wish I knew
early on so bad it would have saved me
so much time would have saved me
headaches because I didn't know when to
stop I didn't know when to call it quits
I didn't know if it was right to call it
quits at five trades a day or 10 trades
a day I didn't know what was right from
wrong I don't recommend any Trader out
there to take more than two trades a day
now it's very hard to say that when I
made that mistake at the beginning
myself but but the reality of the
situation is that if you take more than
two trades a day you're simply not going
to be successful in trading because
you're not taking logical trades there's
no way that the market is giving you a
high probability trade setup more than
two times every single 24 hours around
the clock it's impossible it's not going
to happen this week alone I haven't
taken one single trade and it is
currently Wednesday this whole entire
week so you should not be taking more
than two trades a week this is very key
to your strategy because once again is
going to save you a lot of time from
being in front of the markets doing
nothing and it's going to save you a lot
of money from taking trades that simply
don't make any sense don't make
something out of nothing don't get fomal
the market is not going to go anywhere I
can guarantee you that and this is a
rule that you have to establish and not
break it and whenever you do break it
there has to be a consequence for it
whenever I break my rules I have a
consequence I hate not being able to eat
sweets I love my sweets after dinner
randomly throughout the day but if I
break my rules I can't have sweets for
one or two days that might sound funny
might be you know sound like a joke but
that bothers me I want to have my sweets
why can't I have my sweets and that's
the consequences that I pay for breaking
my rules so you should do the same thing
if you hate cold showers whenever you
break a rule go take a cold shower I can
guarantee you the next time you're going
to think about breaking your rules
you're going think about how bad that
cold shower is going to feel and if you
break your rules and you don't take that
cold shower well you're only doing
damage to yourself cuz you're not
holding yourself accountable you're
being f fake to yourself so if you break
a rule and you brush it off and you
pretend like nobody saw you're right
nobody saw nobody cares cuz you're not
the one that's going to be successful
like nobody cares that you bro they're
going to let you do you you need to hold
yourself accountable whenever you break
rules and have rules that are
unbreakable and if you do break it there
has to be a consequence and again these
are things that I wish that I knew so
early on into my journey it would have
saved me so much time and I'd probably
be on a mega yacht right now who knows I
would have saved 2 years of straight
losses so with all of this information
might be very hard to track it right and
these are just some of the small rules
that I teach my students every single
day because I got on a call with them
every single week and I preach this
every single week every single day like
I'm very hard on them so they stick to
the plan this is only the beginning
there's so many other things that are
needed for this to work I just gave you
the main key components of the engine of
the car I gave you the wheels I gave you
the engine and the transmission now you
need the fuel you need the oil you need
the coolant you need the sparkl you need
the wiring harness you need all of this
other stuff for the car to actually
function you need the details I have
just given you the big car as a whole
I've given you the mask the main things
that you need to actually make it in
trading now it's up to you to actually
learn the details on how to make that
car run and as you're making this car
run as you're trying to put the coolant
put the wire and harness put all this
stuff you might make mistakes you
probably might not want to make them
again that's why I recommend you Journal
every single trade that you take every
single thing everything that you do has
to be journal and sometimes it's very
hard for you to keep track of that
yourself because you either get lazy you
get emotional so I recommend you always
connect your account to a mybook so
myfxbook.com is a very well-known
platform one of the biggest in the
industries as well you just connect your
account into the mybook account and then
there you are simply able to then now
track your trades and you're not able to
track your trades by yourself the
platform does it for you it tells you
your win to loss rate it tells you your
risk to reward ratio it tells you how
long you last in a trade it tells you
the most pairs that you trade it tells
you the session you trade it tells you
what you it tells you everything tells
you more about you than you know about
you and this is very key because it's
going to track not only your performance
but it's going to track your mistakes
and you can go back to the chart and you
can notice these mistakes and you can
learn from it and then you can continue
to not make those mistakes and
capitalize off of them and this is
something that I didn't do for about a
year and a half and as soon as I started
to do it I completely started to shift
my journey because you're seeing the
same mistakes happen again and again and
again and you don't want to keep taking
that cold shower so you're going to
learn from it but sometimes it's hard
for you to remember what caused you to
take that cold shower so that's where
you have these tracking devices and
there's many out there that are very
well and they're very great I just
personally always use the first one that
I was introduced to which is my effects
book and once again took me a while to
find out that platform and what they're
able to do but I'm transferring this to
you guys so I can save you guys the time
and just put you guys on so at this
point I have explained to you the key
parts to having this car built I've
explained to you where you go analyze
the markets I've explained to you where
you execute your trade where you deposit
the money what rules you should have
that are unbreakable where you track
your trades every single tool that I
everything I've given you the full
tutorial on how to day trade now
obviously you need to now have a
strategy you need to have something so
you actually follow every single day
that's why I have students that are
generating anywhere from ,000 to $11,500
a week using my set and forget strategy
literally every single week cuz they got
on a call with me and I Mentor them I
give them my top three top four pairs
for the week I'm in the Discord
answering questions they're in there
with other successful traders that help
them and guide them to take the best
trades possible and I encourage you to
do the same as well because the
community has gotten bigger than ever
and it's letting Traders make anywhere
from ,000 to $1,500 a week using my set
and for strategy so now that you have
the key components to now see what this
car is actually capable of doing now all
you're missing ing is the strategy in
order to actually be able to get this
car to run and take you to success so I
hope you guys have found this video
useful if you want to know more about me
want to know more about the set foret
strategy and how these students are
generating numbers like these or like
these click the link in the description
below I have a video for you there that
explains what set and forget is actually
about and the truth behind the set and
forget strategy and how it's gotten me
to the point where I am today so
appreciate you guys watching this video
all the way to the end make sure to hit
that like And subscribe button and I'll
see you guys in the next video